Emmy Lou Packard
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1919-1990, undated, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-3; 2.6 linear feet)
  Mayer, Ralph (American Artist Magazine), 1975 (2 letters)
  McChesney, Fuller, 1984-1985 (2 letters)
  McChesney, Mary and Robert, 1966-1978 (11 letters)
  McKinney, Joan (Oakland Tribune), 1972 (1 letter)
  McLaughlin, Michael, 1976 (1 letter)
  McQueenie, Claire, 1984-1985 (6 letters)
  McWilliams, Carey (the Nation), 1966 (1 letter)
  McWilliams, Jerry, 1973 (1 letter)
  Medi ?, Lyndall and Chris, 1984 (1 letter)
  Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Library, 1967 (1 letter)
  Mejia, Joy, 1973-1975 (9 letters): see Hathaway, Charles
  Meltzer, Milton, 1976-1977 (4 letters): see California, University of, Berkeley
  Mendocino Historical Society, 1968 (1 letter)
  Merritt Park Corporation, 1972 (1 letter)
  Mesa-Bains, Dr. Amalia, 1984 (1 letter)
  Mexico City Schools and Hospitals, Art Auction to Benefit, 1985 (1 letter)
  Mihalaros, Elizabeth (Mrs. John G. Mihalaros), 1978 (1 letter)
  Miksak, Anthony ("Spike") and Kathi, 1968 (2 letters)
  Miksak, Joe, 1969 (1 letter)
  Harry Miles Printing, 1963 (1 letter)
  Miller, Adam David, 1982-1985 (15 letters)
  Miller, Clem (Congressman), see American Civil Liberties Union
  Miller, Helen Rand, 1966 (1 letter); see Women for Peace
  Miller, Katherine D., 1965 (1 letter)
  Mina Press, 1982-1983 (2 letters)
  Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1981 (1 letter)
  Misrachi, Alberto, 1971 (1 letter) see Maxwell Galleries, Ltd.
  Mitchell, Eloise, 1966 (1 letter)
  Mitford-Truhaft, Decca, 1976 (1 letter)
  Moffat, Samuel, 1974 (2 letters): see Reinhardt, Richard W.
  Mogilevsky, Juriy, 1966 (1 letter)
  Montoya, Emmanuel Catarino and Juana Alica, 1982-1985 (3 letters): see City College of San Francisco
  Mora, E. C. ("Betty"), 1975 (1 letter); see Catlett, E.
  Morgenstern, Sam, 1956 (1 letter)
  Morse, Elsa Peters, 1967 (1 letter)
  Mother Lode Art Association, 1957 (1 letter)
  Moynihan, Daniel Patrick (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Mural Resource Center, 1985 (1 letter)
  Museum of Modern Art, 1983-1989 (4 letters)
  NAACP Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc., 1984 (1 letter)
  Najarian, John, 1976 (1 letter)
  Napa Town and Country Fair, 1967-1968 (2 letters)v Nathan, John J. Nathan and Son, 1974 (2 letters)
  National Observer, The: see Trumbull, Eva London
  NBC Television, 1976 (2 letters)
  Neighborhood Tutorial, The, 1965 (1 letter)
  Neilands, Juanita, 1980-1986 (2 letters)
  Neue Gesellschaft für bildende Kunst (New Society for the Fine Arts), 1982-1985 (4 letters)
  New Diversified Art League Gallery, 1975 (1 letter)
  New World Review, 1964 (6 letters)
  New York Public Library, 1972 (1 letter)
  Nicholson, Jean (Mrs. Donald S. Nicholson), 1971 (1 letter)
  927 Gallery, 1972 (1 letter)
  Nixon, Richard, 1970 (1 letter)
  Noe Valley Ministry, 1985 (1 letter)
  Nolan, Harris, 1973-1974 (4 letters)
  Noon, Brook, 1966 (1 letter)
  Norris, Frank, 1977-1981 (3 letters)
  Oakland Art Museum, 1965 (1 letter)
  Oakland Museum, 1971-1986 (8 letters)
  O'Flaherty, Terrance, 1967 (2 letters)
  Olsen, Tillie, 1965 (1 letter)
  O'Neill, Thomas P. (Speaker of the House), 1983 (1 letter)
  Oregon, University of, Museum of Art, 1978 (1 letter)
  Organization of Solidarity of the Peoples of Africa, Asia and Latin America, 1973 (1 letter)
  Orleans, Peter and Soni, 1968 (1 letter)
  Owen, Louis Jackson ("Jack"), 1972-1980 (28 letters)
  Owen, Mary Ann, 1980 (1 letter)
  PACE (Projects to Advance Creativity in Education), 1966 (1 letter)
  Packard, Elizabeth, see California, University of, Berkeley
  Packard, Emma Leonard, 1963-1980 (22 letters)
  Packard, Emmy Lou, 1935-1985 (30 letters): to Packard's parents mentioning Covarrubias, Frida Kahlo, Orozco, Diego Rivera, and Helena Rubinstein
  Packard, Walter, 1919-1965 (6 letters)
  Papan, Louis J. (California legislature assemblyman), 1983 (1 mailgram)
  Paris, Mr., 1965 (1 letter)
  Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc., 1971 (1 letter)
  Patterson, Leete W., 1982 (1 letter)
  Patterson-Gilmer, Mary Louise, 1980 (1 letter)
  Patton, Rosalie, 1976 (1 letter)
  Paull, Irene, 1965 (1 letter)
  Pavlof, Marian, 1975 (1 letter)
  Payne, Rose, 1978 (1 letter)
  Peninsula School, 1968 (1 letter)
  Peoples' Republic of China, Embassy of, 1972 (3 letters) see Master Travel Corporation; Artists Embassy
  Pera, John Hinchman, 1963 (1 letter)
  Peralta, Roberto B., 1980 (1 letter)
  Percy, Charles H. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Perkins, Dr. Rodney (Stanford Medical School), 1976 (1 letter)
  Perret, Barbara, 1969 (1 letter)
  Petersen, Lonergan and Larson, 1974-1975 (2 letters)
  Petersen, Marie, 1968 (1 letter)
  Pettit, Florence (Mrs. Joseph M. Pettit), 1979 (1 letter)
  Pfeiffer, Pat, 1981 (2 letters)
  Pief, Harry and Barbara, 1984 (1 letter)
  Pitelka, Dorothy and Frank, 1965 (1 letter)
  Pittman, Margrit, 1968-1981 (6 letters)
  Planter Technology, Inc., 1980 (1 letter)
  Potrero Hill Neighborhood House, 1973 (1 letter)
  Private Industry Council of San Francisco, 1985 (1 letter)
  Proxmire, William (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Pushkin Museum (T. Antonava), 1973 (1 letter)
  Puskas-Dresner, Christine, 1985 (2 letters)
  Queen, Christopher Queen and Company, 1978-1980 (6 letters)
  Ramsey, Henry (judge), undated (1 letter)
  Rand, Jack K., 1966 (2 letters)
  Randall, Byron, undated and 1963-1983 (123 letters)
  Randall, Eve (Byron's next wife after Emmy Lou Packard), 1983 (2 letters)
  Randall, Jonathan (Byron's son), undated and 1965-1978 (32 letters)
  Randall, Kenneth and Frances (Byron's parents), 1966-1972 (9 letters)
  Rasmusen, Henry N., 1967 (1 letter)
  Rather, Dan, and Bill Moyers, 1983 (2 letters)
  Raychem Corporation, 1968 (1 letter)
  Reagan, President Ronald, 1982-1983 (2 letters)
  Recreation and Park Department, 1976 (1 letter)
  Refregier, Anton and Lila, 1966-1979 (12 letters)
  Reinhardt, Richard W., 1974 (1 letter)
  Reiss-Konear, Diana, 1983 (1 letter)
  Reuther, Fred G., 1975 (1 letter)
  Reuther, John, 1974 (1 letter)
  Reynolds, Malvina and Bud, n.d and 1965-1971 (12 letters)
  Richanbach, Jean, 1981 (1 letter)
  Richards, Harvey and Alice, 1966-1984 (4 letters)
  Richmond, Nancy (Downtown Peace Coalition), 1970 (2 letters)
  Riegel, Donald W. (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Roberson, Mason (People's World), 1965-1976 (2 letters)
  Robertson, Mary Ann, 1963 (3 letters)
  Roger, Michael B., 1971 (1 letter)
  Romley, Phillip, 1975 (2 letters)
  Roper, Jo, undated (1 postcard)
  Rosenberg Era Art Project (Rob A. Okun), 1985 (1 letter)
  Routa, Mike, 1968 (1 letter)
  Rowe, Frank (Laney College), 1973 (1 letter)
  Ryan, John Allen, 1983 (1 letter)
  Sack, Jeannie, 1981 (1 letter)
  Saint Mary's College, Notre Dame, Indiana, 1968 (2 letters)
  St. Paul's Parish, 1985 (1 letter)
  Safford, Charles, undated and 1953-1955 (8 letters)
  Sampson, Cornelius ("Neil"), 1966-1967 (5 letters)
  Sanford, Nevitt (Stanford University), 1964 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Art Association (Gurdon Woods), 1955 (1 letter): see also Artists Equity Association
  San Francisco Art Commission, 1971-1986 (5 letters)
  San Francisco Art Festival, see Kolmar Associates
  San Francisco Board of Supervisors, 1985 (2 letters)
  San Francisco Chronicle, 1955-1974 (4 letters)
  San Francisco Community Law Collective, 1979 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Examiner, 1970 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Museum of Art, 1950-1965 (6 letters)
  San Francisco Public Library, 1965-1981 (2 letters)
  San Francisco School of the Arts Foundation, 1985 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Society of Women Artists, 1942 (1 letter)
  San Francisco United School District, 1985 (1 letter)
  Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1942 (1 letter)
  Sapinsley, Barbara (CBS News), 1965-1985 (36 letters)
  Sarasohn, Peggy R., 1968 (1 letter)
  Sartain, Gerry, 1967-1975 (5 letters)
  Schneiderman, William and Leah, 1974-1985 (4 letters)
  Schwartz, Carol, 1985 (1 letter)
  Schwendinger, Robert J. (Maritime Humanities Center), 1983-1984 (2 letters)
  Selders, Mike and Mrs., 1966 (2 letters): to Byron Randall
  Shaffer, Bergliot, 1984-1985 (3 letters)
  Shaw, Bob (editor of Oakland paper) and Mary, 1961-1967 (15 letters)
  Shevelyova, Katrina, 1967-1969 (3 letters)
  Shields, Esther (TASS), 1967 (1 letter)
  Shiskaly, Jumif ?, 1953 (2 letters)
  Short, John and Peggy, 1980 (1 letter)
  Silver, Ralph Harper, 1968 (1 letter)
  Smith, Charles L., 1975-1980 (2 letters)
  Smith, Hassel, 1965 (1 letter)
  Smith, Richard ("Dick"), 1978 (1 letter)
  Smithsonian Institution, 1971-1979 (3 letters)
  Sonoma State College, 1976 (3 letters)
  Sordill, Pat, 1984-1985 (4 letters)
  Soviet Woman, 1965-1985 (20 letters)
  Specter, Arlen (Senator), 1984 (1 letter)
  Staats, Redmond, 1968 (1 letter)
  Steele, Philip Steel and Associates, 1968 (2 letters)
  Stegner, Wallace (Stanford University), 1974 (2 letters): see California, University of, Berkeley
  Stern, Thalia (Mrs. Philip B. Stern), 1965-1984 (11 letters)
  Stewart, Alice, 1966 (1 letter)
  Stoll, Jerry (American Documentary Films, Inc.), 1970 (1 letter)
  Storey, Elinor L., 1963 (1 letter)
  Strádalová, Leonora ("Lee"), 1963-1980 (13 letters)
  Strádal, Karel and Lee, 1968 (2 letters)
  Straus, Michael W., 1969 (1 letter)
  Stribling, Mary Lou, 1965-1967 (2 letters)
  Stross, Allen, 1982 (2 letters)
  Suffin, Gloria, 1963 (1 letter) Sunset Lane Magazine Company, 1965 (3 letters)
  Surrendorf, Barbara, 1968 (1 letter)
  Suzuki, Lewis, 1976 (1 letter)
  Sweeting, Ed and Reon, 1965-1985 (4 letters)
  Symms, Steve (Senator), 1984 (1 letter)
  Taylor, Paul, 1962 (1 letter)
  Technical Papers Corp., 1971 (1 letter)
  Teiser, Ruth, 1975 (3 letters)
  Templin, Yvonne, 1965-1971 (9 letters)
  Thompson, David and Butch, 1969 (4 letters)
  Thompson, Elsa Knight, 1966 (1 letter)
  Thompson, Mitsue, 1975 (1 letter)
  Thurmond, Strom (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Timex (Gerald L. White), 1976 (1 letter)
  Treuhaft, Robert (Treuhaft, Jelinek and Samsel), undated (1 letter)
  Trittenbach, Rev. John, 1968 (1 letter)
  Trumbull, Eva London, 1967 (1 letter)
  Tsongas, Paul E. (Senator), 1984 (1 letter)
  Tuominin, Irma M., 1963-1976 (3 letters)
  Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, Embassy of the, 1971-1972 (3 letters)
  United Farm Workers, 1976-1978 (2 letters)
  United States Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (CISPES): 1983-1985 (2 letters)
  United States Delegation, 1965 (1 letter)
  United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1973 (1 letter)
  United States Department of State, 1976 (1 letter)
  United States Treasury Department, 1964 (1 letter)
  Uzbek Friendship Society, 1976-1977 (5 letters)
  Valba Ambulance Project, undated (1 letter)
  Van Dyke, Carl and Andrea, 1972 (1 letter)
  von Ammon, Helen, 1982 (1 letter)
  Ward, Angela, 1980 (1 letter)
  Ward's [catalog] of California, 1965 (1 letter)
  Watkins, J., 1970 (1 letter)
  Watkins, T. H., 1974 (1 letter)
  Watson, Lloyd, 1963 (1 letter)
  Weatherwax, Seema, 1985 (1 letter)
  Webb, Barbara Owen, 1980 (2 letters)
  Weber, Miriam, 1983 (1 letter)
  Weicker, Lowell (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Weilands, Joe and Tor, 1980 (1 letter)
  Welch, David (Ramparts Magazine), 1968 (1 letter)
  White, Jessica, 1969 (1 letter)
  Who's Who in California, 1983 (1 letter)
  Wight, Frank, 1977 (1 letter)
  Wight, Clifford, 1976-1985 (2 letters) Williams, Ferne (Mrs. Edward Williams), 1984 (1 letter)
  Williams, Sydney H. (Williams, Cook and Mocine) and Margaret, 1966-1974 (2 letters)
  Wilson, Edmund "Scoop," 1964 (2 letters)
  Wilson, Judge, 1972 (1 letter)
  Wilson, Pete (Senator), 1983 (1 letter)
  Windmiller, Marshall and Myra, 1966 (2 letters)
  Winter, Betty, 1963 (1 letter)
  Wolff, Ashley, 1984 (1 letter)
  Wolff, Dr. Ernst and Mrs. (Leona Bayer), 1967-1985 (10 letters)
  Wolff, Bill, 1981-1985 (2 letters): see Guttmann, Ethel Weiner
  Women for Peace, 1964 (2 letters): see Hamburg, Alice (Women's International League for Peace)
  Women's Caucus for Art, 1979-1980 (6 letters)
  Women's History Research Center, Inc., 1973-1975 (4 letters)
  Wong, Victor, 1971 (1 letter)
  Wood, Mireille P., 1981 (1 letter)
  Woods, Gurdon, 1963 (7 letters): see also Artists Equity Association; San Francisco Art Association
  Wurster, Catherine, 1960 (1 letter)
  Zakheim, Bernard Baruch, 1968 (1 letter)
  Zellerbach, Harold L., 1955 (1 letter)
  Ziegler, William, 1989 (1 letter)
  Zimmerman, Alan, 1985 (1 letter)
  Zimmerman, Susan, 1970 (1 letter)
  - First Names Known, undated (Box 1, Reel 5812)
  - Surnames Beginning with A -L, undated (Box 1, Reel 5812)
  - Surnames Beginning with M - Z, undated (Box 1, Reel 5812)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1919-September, 1969, (53 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5812)
  - Chronological Correspondence, September, 1969 - December, 1971, (18 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5813)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January, 1972 - November, 1980, (66 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5813)
  - Chronological Correspondence, December, 1980 - December, 1981, (7 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5814)
  - Chronological Correspondence, December, 1980 - December, 1981, (7 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5814)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January, 1982 - 1990, (39 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Chronological Correspondence, December, 1980 - December, 1981, (7 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5814)
- Personal Business Records, 1945-1985, undated, Series 3:; (Box 3; 21 folders)
  Personal business records arranged chronologically that document many of Packard's business and personal transactions not directly associated with specific projects. This series includes a contract, real estate records, rent records, insurance records, price lists for art prints, consignment records for galleries and art centers, and receipts.
  - Contract with Alfonso Pardinas, 1957 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Real Estate Records, 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Rent Records, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Insurance Records, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Price Lists for Prints, 1962-1981 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Gallery West 1970-1974 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Mendocino Art Center, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Collectors Graphics, 1973 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Collectors Gallery, Oakland Museum 1973-1979, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Gallery Fair, Mendocino Gallery, 1973-1979, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Pines and Needles, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, March Gallery, Roy Boyd Gallery, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Specialty Art of California, Inc., 1975 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Consignment Records, Mary Williams, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Receipts, 1945-1985, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5814)
- Interview Transcript, 1979, Series 4:; (Box 3; 1 folder)
  Transcript of an interview of Emmy Lou Packard by Louise Gilbert for the Radical Elders Oral History Project, "The Early Years," 1979.
  - Transcript of an interview of Packard by Louise Gilbert, 1979 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
- Notes, 1900-1985, Series 5:; (Boxes 3-4, 10; 1.1 linear foot)
  This series consists primarily of numbered notebook/diaries that briefly annotate Packard's daily activities and meetings, thoughts, medications, and food consumption. There are also address lists, minutes of meetings for the Artists Equity Association, membership lists and newsletters for the Graphic Arts Workshop, and notes on various political and social matters, Mexico, and miscellaneous topics. Included in this series are 3 folders of notes on family history, including notes on Elizabeth Ware Packard and Walter Packard, Emmy Lou's father, as well as biographical accounts of Packard's grandparents Samuel and Clara Packard, and a photograph of Packard's great-grandparents Theophilus and Elizabeth Ware Packard. Also found is a file of notes relating to therapy sessions with Dr. Arthur Bazell.
  - Notebook/Diaries #1, #2, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Reel 5814)
  - Notebook/Diaries #3, #4, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Reel 5815)
  - Notebook/Diaries #5-#21, 1956-1985, (13 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5815)
  - Notebook/Diaries #22, #23, 1985 (Box 4, Reel 5815)
  - Notebook/Diaries #22, #23 (Continued from Reel 5815), 1985 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Annotated Wall Calendars (see also Box 10), 1974 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes of Conversations with Dr. Arthur Bazell (therapist), 1972 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Mailing and Address Lists, 1969-1985, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Artists Equity Association Meeting Minutes, 1949-1956, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Graphic Arts Workshop Newsletters and Member List, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Family History Notes, 1900-1978 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Elizabeth Ware Packard, undated (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Walter Packard (father), 1944-1974 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Alonzo Aquilar (Mexican economist), undated (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Alexander Gumberg (former secretary to Lenin), 1924-1966 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Frederick Douglas, 1972 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Alonzo Aquilar (Mexican economist), undated (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Political and Social Issues, 1956-1971, undated, (4 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Alonzo Aquilar (Mexican economist), undated (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Mexico, 1971-1982, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Song Lyrics, 1946, undated (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on Tide Pool Aquariums, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Notes on San Francisco City Planning Code, 1967-1974 (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1964-1985, undated, (4 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5816)
  - Oversized Annotated Wall Calendar, 1983 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5816)
- Reference Files on Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, 1929-1986, Series 6:; (Box 5, 10, OV 11; 0.9 linear feet)
  This series houses correspondence, notes, writings, photographs, and printed material documenting Packard's close business and personal relationship with Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, including Packard's research for her planned, but unpublished book on the couple. The correspondence includes letters from Rivera, Kahlo, and Mexican mural painters Juan O'Gorman and Pablo O'Higgins. Photographs in this series include those of Rivera, Kahlo, Packard and others, both individually and together; many are quite personal and rare. Included are photographs of Rivera painting a portrait of Frances Rich; Rivera with Rich; Rivera holding hands with Packard; Rivera and Packard at the Alamo; Rivera and Packard in Coyoacan, Mexico, photographed by Kahlo; Kahlo and Packard photographed by Rivera; Rivera eating; Rivera playing with a spider monkey; Kahlo sitting in doorway; Rivera and Kahlo at lunch in Coyoacan, Mexico; Kahlo in jeans leaning against a wall; Rivera with pre-Columbian stone figures. This series also includes sketches by Rivera, Kahlo, and Covarrubias.
  The correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  See index for Notable Correspondents from Series 6: Reference File on Diego River and Frida Kahlo
  Index: Notable Correspondents from Series 6: Reference File on Diego River and Frida Kahlo
  American Russian Institute, 1975 (1 letter)
  Arnautoff, Victor, 1975 (1 letter)
  Bancroft, Elizabeth, 1983-1984 (2 letters)
  Banks, Fred (Harcourts Gallery), 1984 (3 letters)
  Beatty, Don, 1982-1985 (3 letters): see Mexican Museum
  Beraza, Felipe Garcia, 1981 (2 letters)
  Bribriesca, Jorge, 1983 (1 letter)
  California Arts Council, 1976-1977 (2 letters)
  California, University of, Berkeley, 1977 (1 letter)
  Clayburg, Mrs., see Rivera, Diego
  Colina, Armando (Galeria Arvil), see Banks, Fred (Harcourts Gallery)
  Cortez, Raymundo Acosta, 1974
  Detroit Institute of Arts, 1983-1985 (2 letters)
  Dimitroff, Lucienne Bloch, 1976-1986 (5 letters)
  Dreher, Robert, undated (1 letter)
  Dubinsky, David, see Rivera, Diego
  Editorial Advisor, 1982 (1 letter)
  Erb, Guy Feliz and Iva, 1983-1984 (8 letters)
  Fonda, Mrs. Henry, see Rivera, Diego
  Ford Motor Company, undated (1 card)
  Galeria de la Raza/Studio 24, 1978-1984 (3 letters)
  Garcia, Rupert, 1981 (1 letter)
  Goldblatt, Louis (International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union) and Terry, 1983 (1 letter)
  Goodman, Michael, 1977-1981 (2 letters)
  Greenfield, Gary (Shartsis, Friese and Ginsburg), 1980 (9 letters): see Harper and Row
  Guggenheim, Barbara Guggenheim Publications, 1983 (1 letter)
  Hall, John (Color 2000), 1981-1983 (3 letters)
  Harper and Row, 1980 (2 letters)
  Herrera, Hayden, 1978-1980 (2 letters)
  Hess, Sally (Mrs. Frank Hess), 1983 (1 letter)
  Hoffman, Mona, see Lapworth, Norman
  Homolka, Oscar, see Rivera, Diego
  Institute of Soviet American Relations, 1975 (1 letter)
  Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes, 1982-1983 (4 letters)
  Jones, Mary Ellen, 1982 (1 letter)
  Journeyman Press, 1984 (1 letter)
  Kahlo, Frida, undated and 1940-1941 (6 letters, including 2 with lipstick kiss imprints) see Lapworth, Norman and Mona Hoffman
  Kaplan, Sidney (The Massachusetts Review), 1977-1978 (2 letters)
  Lancaster-Miller, Inc., 1981-1984 (7 letters)
  Lapworth, Norman and Mona Hoffman, undated and 1972 (2 letters, including telegram to Frida Kahlo from Mona Hoffman)
  Lovestone, Jay, see Rivera, Diego
  Marin, Guadalupe, 1942 (1 letter)
  Mendez, Ernesto R. (Palacio Nacional), see Rivera, Diego
  Mexican Museum, 1981-1983 (4 letters,including one to Pablo O'Higgins)
  Moreno, Mario, see Zamora, Martha
  Museo Tamayo, 1983 (1 letter, re Rivera illustrations and Dolores Olmedo)
  Myron's Dye Transfer (Mr. Holmes), 1983 (1 letter)
  New York Times, 1981 (1 letter)
  O'Gorman, Juan, Elena (Helen), Bunny, undated and 1972-1983 (29 letters)
  O'Higgins, Pablo and Maria, 1961-1983 (7 letters): see Mexican Museum; Randall, Byron
  Olmedo, Dolores ("Lola"), 1976-1984 (3 letters) see Banks, Fred (Harcourts Gallery); Erb, Guy Feliz; Museo Tamayo; Martha Zamora
  Oppenheimer, Frank, 1984 (1 letter): see Scientists for Peace in Central America
  Ramparts Press, 1973-1984 (11 letters)
  Randall, Byron, 1982 (1 letter, to Pablo and Maria O'Higgins)
  Reynolds, Malvina, 1977 (1 letter)
  Rivera, Diego, undated and 1929-1941 (25 letters)
  Robinson, Edward G., see Rivera, Diego
  Rodriguez, Patricia, 1985 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Art Institute, 1981-1986 (2 letters)
  San Francisco Chronicle, 1981-1984 (4 letters)
  San Francisco Examiner, 1984 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Museum of Art, 1940-1948 (2 letters, including one to Diego Rivera: see Rivera, Diegof)
  Scientists for Peace in Central America, 1984 (1 letter)
  Skyline College, 1977 (1 letter)
  Solomon, Peter: see Ramparts Press
  Stendahl, Earl: see Rivera, Diego
  Tejada-Flores, Rick, 1981 (3 letters)
  Temko, Allan, 1982 (2 letters)
  Unidad de Television Educativa y Cultural, México, 1982 (1 letter)
  Vargas, Gilberto Mendoza, 1982 (1 letter)
  Wachs, Henry, 1982-1983 (2 letters)
  Ward, Estolve, 1983 (1 letter)
  White, Mrs. Alan, 1983 (1 letter)
  Wilson, Edmund: see Reynolds, Malvina
  Zamora, Martha, 1982-1985 (25 letters)
  - Chronological Correspondence (includes letters from Kahlo and Rivera), 1929 - June 1983, undated, (26 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5816)
  - Chronological Correspondence (includes letters from Kahlo and Rivera), July, 1983 - 1986, (7 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Receipts and Invoices, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Caricatures of Rivera drawn on a menu by Covarrubias, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)